{
    "version": 2.0,
    "questions": [{
            "question": "Q1. The electrode potential measures the _____________",
            "answers": {
                "a": "The tendency of the electrode to gain or lose electrons.",
                "b": "Possibility of a cell reaction to occur.",
                "c": "Current.",
                "d": "The difference in the ionization of electrode and metal ion."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q2. Which of the following is not a part of the three-electrode system?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Auxiliary electrode.",
                "b": "Working electrode.",
                "c": "Reference electrode.",
                "d": "Conducting electrode."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "d"
        }, {
            "question": "Q3. In anodic stripping voltammetry, the deposition step is:",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Reduction",
                "b": "Oxidation.",
                "c": "Unnecessary.",
                "d": "Reduction and oxidation."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q4. What are the common parameters involved in voltammetry?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Current and electrodes.",
                "b": "Potential and current.",
                "c": "Current and resistance.",
                "d": "Potential and resistance."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q5. For which of the following technique, the potential waveform is a series of potential pulses of increasing amplitude, with potential returning to the baseline each time?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Differential pulse voltammetry.",
                "b": "Stripping voltammetry.",
                "c": "Normal pulse voltammetry.",
                "d": "Differential pulse anodic stripping voltammetry."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q6. Which of the following curve is obtained during the voltammetric analysis of an electroactive analyte?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Charge time curve.",
                "b": "Current-potential curve.",
                "c": "Current-time curve.",
                "d": "Charge temperature curve."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }, {
            "question": "Q7. Which of the following is an advantage of the dropping mercury electrode?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "A fresh reaction surface is provided with each drop of mercury so that material does not accumulate at the electrode.",
                "b": "It is a less expensive electrode.",
                "c": "It is comparatively easier to obtain.",
                "d": "It can drive a reaction at a low temperature."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q8. In ASV, the metal ions in a sample are concentrated onto the electrode surface by application of a ___________",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Negative potential.",
                "b": "Positive potential.",
                "c": "Negative current.",
                "d": "Positive current."
            },
            "correctAnswer": "a"
        }, {
            "question": "Q9. Which of the following electrodes are often used as counter or auxiliary electrode in voltammetry?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Calomel electrode",
                "b": "Carbon paste",
                "c": "Platinum wire",
                "d": "Mercury thin film"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "c"
        }, {
            "question": "Q10. Which of the following voltammetric techniques enhances the sensitivity through improving the faradaic current?",
            "answers": {
                "a": "Differential pulse voltammetry",
                "b": "Square wave voltammetry",
                "c": "Cyclic voltammetry",
                "d": "Stripping voltammetry"
            },
            "correctAnswer": "b"
        }
    ]
}